Jace Browning

I build, customize, integrate, and teach engineering software tools. With degrees in computer engineering and computer science, I am familiar with software development across multiple industries on a variety of platforms. I've worked on products in the embedded, mobile, and web space, but my expertise is Python programming. Sharing knowledge and active involvement in the local tech community are integral parts of my life and career.

Experience

Zapier Remote

Senior Test Automation Engineer

Sep 2017 - Present

Architected CI/CD pipelines augmented with custom test management services and frameworks.

- Built Zapier's first end-to-end testing pipeline using a custom Selenium-based framework
- Created a metrics-driven incident response process and corresponding ChatOps automation
- Developed a service to track test suite duration and automatically disable flakey tests
- Migrated delivery pipelines through an evolution of Jenkins, Drone, Travis, and finally GitLab
- Codified CI/CD best-practices into Django/Next.js, used to generate dozens of new services

ClickFunnels Remote

Quality Assurance Engineer

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017

Bridged the gap between Infrastructure and Testing through tooling and automation.

- Standardized Continuous Integration tooling between Rails, Ember, and Node applications
- Automated AWS CloudFormation infrastructure using SparkleFormation and Chef
- Built a deployment service to synchronize test environments to GitHub pull requests
- Facilitated the refactoring of a legacy Rails codebase to streamline feature development

Modustri Grand Rapids, MI

Quality Assurance and DevOps Lead

Apr 2015 - Jun 2016

Managed testing and releases for a heavy-duty equipment inspection platform.

- Set up Continuous Integration for a Rails/Node/Python backend and iOS/Ember frontend
- Set up Continuous Deployment into dev/staging environments for all product components
- Exploratory Tested all new features and bug fixes using a GitHub pull request workflow
- Managed monthly production releases through an end-to-end test suite and deploy scripts

Adonit Grand Rapids, MI

Quality Assurance Lead

Oct 2014 - Mar 2015

Created the process and tooling necessary to bring a complex iPad sketching and ideation app to production and reach Editor's Choice with more than 250k users.

- Proposed and trained the team on optimal GitHub code review and branching strategies
- Configured and maintained a TeamCity CI server with multiple provisioned build agents
- Developed Python and Shell scripts to automate builds, testing, and static analysis

DornerWorks Grand Rapids, MI

Software Engineer

Oct 2013 - Oct 2014

Developed and tested products for several clients to quality standards set by their applicable regulatory industries. Reworked the entire internal Python development stack to promote automation.

- Deployed an extension to the Buildbot CI framework for desktop and embedded software
- Developed a Python framework to automate the testing of a VxWorks-based medical device

Johnson Controls, Inc.

Holland, MI

Software Engineer

May 2011 - Oct 2013

Technical lead for two production releases of vehicle Bluetooth audio systems. Mentored a dozen entry through senior-level engineers developing HMI software on an embedded Linux platform. Developed an array of tools to facilitate proper software testing and version control practices.

- Created a GUI to simulate infotainment applications from design specifications
- Built a test framework in Python to emulate UI interaction for integration testing

Eaton Aerospace Grand Rapids, MI

Software Engineer

May 2007 - May 2011

Involved in the entire airborne software lifecycle compliant with RTCA DO-178B standards. Led development and testing of a post-certification software release of a fly-by-wire flap system.

Education

Grand Valley State University

Grand Rapids, MI

Computer Science, M.S.

2010 - 2013

- 3.9 GPA
- Emphasis on distributed computing, mobile technologies, and requirements management
- Charter member of West Michigan Tau Beta Pi and GVSU Engineering alumni chapters

Grand Rapids, MI

Grand Valley State University

Computer Engineering, B.S.

2005 - 2009

- 3.7 GPA
- Honors College and Tau Beta Pi member
- Awarded Outstanding Senior Project and Outstanding Computer Engineering Graduate

jacebrowning.info